Jesus is on the throne.
Tell your neighbour, "Jesus is on the throne".
Hallelujah!
I want to salute our viewers.
Whatever medium you are using to view us, thank you for your time.
Hallelujah!
For some weeks now, we have been talking about challenges - what does this mean to you,
and what does this mean to me, as a Christian?
Because of the situation we are in...
We seem to be in perilous times – a time that looks so strange.
You have no word to define it.
What is happening in your country is what is happening in another country.
Everywhere:
economic oppression,
political oppression,
religious oppression,
institutionalised corruption everywhere.
What are you waiting for?
Will you be ready when the Lord shall come
I will be ready
When the Lord shall come
Did you listen to that?
Will you be ready?
Yes – the signs we are seeing show that you should be ready.
Don’t allow the challenges or situation you are facing to cause you
to overthrow your position before God.
What are the challenges?
You know the challenges you are going through.
The challenge, as a Christian, is meant to strengthen our desire and determination for God.
The more that challenge, the more you see God clearer,
the more you pray and fast, the more your desire.
You may be seated, thank you.
Hallelujah!
Today, we take our reading from the Book of Matthew 16 - that will be our proof reading.
Another reading: you take the Book of 1 Peter, chapter 5 - start your reading from verse 8,
8, 9, 10 - that will really help you to understand, to have an insight of what we are about to talk about.
2 Timothy would also be a better reading for you -
2 Timothy, chapter 3 - you take your reading from verse 10 to the end.
The Book of Hebrews 3 - take your reading from verse 6.
I want to believe you are there.
Are you there?
I hope your mind is not divided because I need your heart.
Lord I want to be like Jesus
Inner my heart
Not just your appearance but your heart.
If your heart is not here, who am I talking to?
I am talking in vain.
Your heart is the strong room, the prayer room, the contact point.
When I say, ‘your heart,’ I mean, ‘your spirit’.
Your sprit is what the Holy Spirit will use to express Himself – through your heart.
Are your here?
Hallelujah!
If you are here; look at me - what are you seeing?
You are seeing a jacket - you are not here.
If you are here, you will not see this jacket, you will not even see this appearance.
You will not see a man looking like your brother.
Beyond that man is the Man you are here for.
Also, in the Book of John 15 - it will help you, and Romans 1, verse 14 - that will really help you.
Let's start our reading - Matthew 16.
“The Pharisees and Sadducees came to Jesus and tested him
by asking him to show them a sign from Heaven.”
That is the question I'm asking you now, "Are you here?"
This is a piece of Heaven on earth – it is an extension.
What we are about to do is an extension.
Let's go to the proof text in verse 24.
“Then Jesus said to his disciples, ‘Whoever wants to be my disciple must deny themselves...'"
Whoever wants to follow me must do what?
[Deny yourself.]
That is for you; you insert your name where the message is personal.
Here, it seems to be too personal.
If I want to be His disciple, follower, I must do what?
[Deny myself.]
How do we deny ourselves?
By putting on suit, wig, powder, jeep...
OK, that is it.
"'... and take up their cross and follow me'."
Are you taking your cross?
Deny yourself and take up your cross and follow Jesus.
Hallelujah!
And it says further:
“For whoever wants to save their life will lose it, but whoever loses their life for me will find it.”
When you take your time to read, you will see that salvation is more than just saying,
“Lord Jesus, I am a sinner”.
Altar call everywhere.
Many of you have given your life to Jesus.
You give your life to yourself.
Salvation is more than just saying,
"Hey, altar call!" - you rush out, you come out.
“Lord Jesus, I am a sinner; come into my heart. Wash me with Your precious blood."
He is lying.
“Save my soul today” – then going on your merry way.
Salvation is more than that.
Salvation is a total and complete commitment to Jesus.
OUR COMMITMENT TO JESUS
Oh how I love Jesus
Because He went for me
If you love someone, love is a thing of heart; love is not a thing of mouth.
That is why marriage is crumbling today;
because we see that he loves someone because she is beautiful, because of accent,
"My husband can speak very well. I love him. I want to marry him".
You love someone because of their attire, appearance - no!
Love is a thing of heart.
When heart is involved – total and complete commitment.
"How I love Jesus!"
You cannot get Jesus to forgive your sins without making a commitment to Him.
Tell your neighbour,
“I cannot get Jesus to forgive my sins without total commitment,
without making a commitment to Him.”
Salvation is not just merely saying, “Lord Jesus, come into my heart.
Wash me with Your precious blood. Save my soul today”.
That is why people are not saved today.
You see questionable born-again, believers, Christians.
Knowing facts about Jesus does not change our relationship with Him.
"Jesus is my Lord, Saviour, Healer, I'm born-again..."
Knowing facts about Him does not change our relationship with Him.
This is what the Book of Matthew 16:24 and Matthew 10:38 is saying.
Jesus said if you do not take up your cross and deny yourself
and perhaps even get killed for your belief in Him, you are not worthy of Him.
Worthy You are worthy
King of kings Lord of lords
You are worthy
Worthy You are worthy
King of kings Lord of lords
I worship You
If you do not take up your cross and deny yourself
and perhaps even get killed for your belief in Him, you are not worthy of Him.
Who is Jesus?
His worshippers must worship Him in truth and Spirit.
Get to Him in truth and Spirit.
Talk to Him in truth and Spirit.
Worship Him in truth and Spirit.
Admire Him in truth and Spirit.
Pray to Him in truth and Spirit.
Jesus is not going to give salvation to those who do not endure to the end.
He will come like a thief in the night.
No one knows when or how.
The beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
He is not going to give salvation to those who will not endure to the end.
What manner of man is Jesus?
OUR COMMITMENT TO JESUS
Total and complete commitment to Jesus.
We literally sell ourselves to Him.
We are then debtors.
We no longer belong to ourselves; we are servants.
I want to move my leg; I need to consult Him, because I no longer belong to myself,
"Jesus!".
I want to wear suit, "Jesus!"
You don’t know how much you need Him; that is why your life is like this.
You only need Him when you have problems, when you are sick.
When you have challenges, when you have difficulties, you need Jesus.
You don’t know how much you need Him.
What kind of life is that?
It means you are not a servant.
Tell your neighbour,
"You don't know how much you need Jesus."
You only need Him when you have challenges; you need Him when you have difficulties.
That is when you need Jesus.
You must know how much you need Him.
Because we no longer belong to ourselves; we are then debtors.
The word ‘commitment’ is neither taught nor practised today.
In Romans 1:14, Paul said, “I am a debtor”.
Christ bought Paul even as He bought us.
This means salvation is a sale; it is a transaction.
Christ bought and paid for us.
What a terrible price Christ had to pay for us!
He paid a debt He did not owe
I owed a debt I could not pay
I needed Someone to wash my sins away
Now I can sing a brand new song
Amazing grace
Lord Jesus paid a debt that I could never pay
He paid a debt He did not owe
I owed a debt I could not pay
I needed Someone to wash my sins away
Now I can sing a brand new song
Amazing grace
Lord Jesus paid a debt that I could never pay
You may be seated.
Hallelujah!
I don’t think enough people understand this:
The level at which satan attacks us seems to be equal to the level of our commitment to Him.
This is why I said I don’t think enough people understand this.
The level at which satan attacks us seems to be equal to the level of our commitment to God.
- "Oh, what is this man saying?"
- "Yes!"
Job was totally committed to God Almighty.
That is the reason God was willing to take up satan’s challenge against him.
If you are totally committed to God Almighty, He will take up satan’s challenge against you.
Tell your neighbour.
If you are totally committed to God, God will take up satan’s challenge against you.
"I have this, that" - no!
The life you live is no longer yours.
We no longer belong to ourselves; whatever you are facing is Christ’s.
You face challenges – Christ’s.
You face sickness – Christ’s.
You face this - Christ's.
You feel it so much because you are not living for Christ; you are not committed to Christ.
In John 15, as soon as you become born again, as soon as you make a conversion,
then, satan hates you the same as he hates Jesus.
Tell your neighbour:
“As soon as you make a conversion, I mean, as soon as you become born again,
as soon as you are saved, then, satan hates you the same as he hates Jesus.”
The moment you are saved, you are engaged in a phenomenal battle.
Are you with me?
The moment you are saved, the moment you are born again,
the moment you have become a believer, truly, the moment you are truly born again,
you are engaged in a phenomenal battle.
Not just battle - no!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is not a battle of flesh and blood – like the kind of enemy you have today.
You say your brother hates you and your brother has flesh and blood.
I don’t know the kind of enemy you have.
You say, "That my brother hates me" - no!
Our hate is towards spirit being, not towards your brother.
Your enemy is not your brother; your enemy is not your husband.
Your enemy is not your wife; your enemy is not the chairman of your company.
Your enemy is not your mentor but spirit beings that cause tension and pressure.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why you always fail the battle.
You fail the battle all the time because you see your brother as your enemy.
You always fail the battle.
If you want to become victorious in whatever you lay your hand, in whatever you attempt,
see spirit beings as your enemy that cause tension and pressure; you will overcome.
Many of you were saying, "T.B. Joshua is this, that".
You really persecuted me in those days.
I don't see you as a persecutor.
I see that being pushing you to do that.
If somebody comes to me and says, "Hey!", I look at you and want to know who is backing you -
that evil power that is backing you.
That is why I cannot reply; I don't reply people, I don't reply flesh and blood.
I don't reply, I just look at you.
They say, "This man - they keep abusing him, he will not reply".
Whom will I reply?
Flesh and blood?
But I battle the spirit being that is pushing you to say this or that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But you keep busy, fighting your brother.
Your brother will say to you,
"You are foolish".
"You call me foolish? You will see!"
It is not that your brother that calls you foolish.
Your brother cannot call you foolish, if there is no evil spirit behind him to say that.
You always engage in a failed battle.
Tell your neighbour, “You engage in a failed battle”.
Tell your neighbour.
[You engage in a failed battle.]
I cannot hear you.
The moment you become born again, then, satan hates you.
I am not saying, “The moment you become born again, then, your brother hates you”.
Did I say that?
"The moment you become born again, then, your husband hates you" - did I say that?
But that is the battle you are fighting.
You fight your husband, wife, uncle, cousin, the person... - no!
The moment you become born again, then, satan hates you the same as he hates Jesus.
The moment you are truly born again, you are engaged in a phenomenal battle.
If it had not been for the Lord
Who was always on my side
The enemy would have swallowed us
We would have drowned in their waters
But our souls have found an escape
A hiding place in You
The fowler’s snare is broken
Our help is in the name of the Lord
I’m nothing without You
You are the air that I breathe
Can’t live without You
In You I live and move and have my being
Hosanna to Jehovah
You are the air that I breathe
Hallelujah Hallelujah
In You I live and move and have my being
I’m nothing without You
You are the air that I breathe
Can’t live without You
In You I live and move and have my being
Without who?
Without your husband?
Without your wife?
Without T.B. Joshua?
Without your cousin?
Without your mentor?
Why are you fighting flesh and blood?
Why are you fighting a failed battle?
If you look at your record, all the battles you have been fighting -
in 90% of your battles you failed, because you are fighting a wrong battle.
Instead of fighting the spirit being that causes the tension and pressure, it is...
Oh, my God.
Failed battle.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The moment you accept Jesus as your Lord and Saviour, truly,
then, satan hates you the same as he hates Jesus.
As you accept Jesus as your Lord and Saviour, commitment asks Jesus to accept you.
Your faithfulness to Jesus, "My Lord, Jesus - my Saviour. I accept Jesus."
Before you can be accepted, commitment will be the one to ask Jesus to accept you.
Your faithfulness, your kindness, your obedience, love unconditional,
will be the one to ask Jesus to accept you.
Then, you become Jesus’ property.
The level at which satan attacks you seems to be equal to the level of your commitment to God.
Tell your neighbour.
[The level at which satan attacks you seems to be equal to the level of your commitment to God.]
Again.
You may be seated, thank you.
OUR COMMITMENT TO JESUS
If you are committed, Jesus will take up satan’s challenge against you.
What is satan’s challenge against you?
Stagnation, nightmare, weakness - Jesus will take it up.
Tell your neighbour:
"If you are committed to God, Jesus will take up satan’s challenge against you."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Did you listen to that?
Viewers, all over the world:
If truly you are committed to the Lord, you get involved in God’s projects,
Jesus will take up satan’s challenge against you
because we no longer belong to ourselves; we are servants.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It’s not by power
It’s not by might
By My Spirit says the Lord
Listen to that.
This mountain has been removed
That is the challenge.
This mountain has been removed in Jesus' name
This mountain must be removed in Jesus’ name
By My Spirit says the Lord
The mountain is satan’s challenge.
Jesus will take it up.
Can you see - you sing the song, you don't know what you are saying.
This sickness, this affliction, this stagnation, this setback...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Before you...
You see many of them are here today.
Before they could come here, they had been to witch doctors.
Many have joined occultic practices, but when they realised that there is no way,
"Let me go and see that Jesus".
Many of us are here today, your potential – many have given this potential to satan.
It is counterfeit they are carrying to Jesus – counterfeit body.
When you had ..., you carried it to satan.
But now...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me?
When you were ... - Hi" - you gave it to the world.
But now...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Sometimes, when I see people, as if I should give you a "blow".
Each time I want to give a blow, Jesus will hold my hand.
I say, "Oh Jesus, let me give that blow. Why are they giving You this?
When they were like this, they were in the world!"
When your teeth were shining, you were in the world, but now your teeth are decayed.
When they say, "Praise God!", you see the teeth.
"My God!"
I say, "Look at the teeth. All these teeth are dirty".
The very fine teeth - satan has taken them.
Go and bring that fine teeth back.
Thank you.
Thank You, Lord.
TT ROBERT BEGIER 13/08/2018
RV: Mel Flowers 13/08/2018